This week, we got a new open weight
model that is really, really impressive.
We got some cool new video editing
tools, an AI image generator that
promises consistent characters, and so
much more this week. I don't want to
waste your time, so let's get right into
it. Starting with this new large
language model called GLM 4.5. Now, when
I first came across this model, I was
actually going to push it towards the
end of the video because I'm not really
that into models that just show like
marginal improvements over what we've
already got. I mean, if we look at this
new GLM 4.5 model, it is an open weight
model, meaning that you can download the
weights and use them on your own
computer or you can run them on a cloud
computer and do whatever you want with
them. And it holds up against the
state-of-the-art models that are out
there. So if we do look at these
benchmark charts here, we can see this
GLM 4.5 performs almost as well as Gro 4
and ChatGpt's 03 and actually performed
better than Claude 4 Opus on agentic
reasoning and coding benchmarks. Again,
I personally pay less and less attention
to benchmarks. I want to see something
that when I use it, I'm just genuinely
impressed by it. And this model, when I
went and used it for the first time, I
was genuinely impressed by it,
especially for an openweight model
that's freely available for anybody to
use. You can actually head on over to
Z.ai and use this fully for free. And
one of the party tricks of this model
that is really cool is that it can
create slide decks. You select AI
slides. Here you can see that it will
use image search, web search, and
slidemaker to actually make you a slide
deck. Just for fun, I gave it the prompt
a slide deck about how birds aren't
real. And look, it went through and did
all of this research for me and then
built out a slide deck. So, it searched
for information on the birds aren't real
movement, visited Wikipedia, continued
to read Wikipedia, visited the New York
Times, read a 60-minute article about
it, searched for relevant images,
searched for images of the founder of
the movement, then started to create the
slide deck, and then you can see it
created the first, second, third, etc.
slides. And when all was said and done,
it made this slide deck that genuinely
impressed me. So, you can see it's got
birds aren't real, the satirical
conspiracy theory, some explanation
about it. I love this little saying, if
it flies, it spies. Details about the
founder and the origins, and it even put
a picture of the founder here with like
a quote and details about him. Key
claims and evidence. It's actually got a
picture of a fake bird here with like
the conspiracy details and the evidence
presented, the growth and cultural
impact, a million followers. I mean,
these slides actually look like decent
slides. The satirical nature with more
details, more photos, and then the final
slide here. So, it made six slides, but
they're all really, really good-looking.
For comparison, a few weeks ago, I had
ChatGpt generate a slide deck, and this
was the slide deck that it generated.
So, you can see the slides are all just
white rectangles with some black text.
Yeah, there's some charts and stuff
here, but they don't look anywhere near
as good as what this new model created
for a slide deck. Like, to me, these
slides look really, really impressive.
It's also really good at writing code
and just like oneshotting whatever app
you wanted to create. For example,
create a clone of Vampire Survivors in
JavaScript that I can play in the
browser. I'll go ahead and submit this
prompt here, and we can see that it is a
thinking model. So, it's going to think
through and now it's just starting to
write the code for me. And as it's doing
that, I should mention that this model
is extremely fast and so far totally
free to use. I mean, there hasn't been
anywhere where it's asked me to pay to
use it. I'm using it directly on their
website using their servers, their
cloud. No payment whatsoever. Now, they
do have an API, so my guess is they're
going to generate revenue by getting
people to use the API. But here we go.
Here's the game. This is one-shotted.
And we can see it's making a little
flash circle that is like hurting the
enemies as they get closer to me. I
could dodge the enemies. Now, it
obviously doesn't have the graphics of
Vampire Survivors. I didn't give it any,
you know, any graphics to play with, but
the concept is there. I mean, it's a
swarm of enemies coming towards the
character and the character just auto
fires its weapon and hurts the enemies
that get near it. And then I collect
little XP points. And then let's see.
Let's put on throw knives. Let's see if
it actually it actually does throw kn.
Look at that. throws the dives and we've
got a weapon that's shooting in four
different directions now and I'm
leveling up. Let's used garlic and it's
worked. This was one shot. I literally
gave it no other prompts. So, if I
wanted to now I can go and replace all
the little dots with actual like
character graphics, but the actual
gameplay of the Vampire Survivors like
bullet hell style of game works. Like
one prompt and it worked. Like it it's
really really good. And it's an
openweight model. Like this model is
blowing my mind right now. Again, I tend
to not get in the weeds whenever there's
a new large language model that comes
out that feels marginally more
impressive than what was already there,
but this one feels like way more
impressive, especially for an openweight
model. So, really, really cool model,
GLM4.5.
You can play around with it over at
z.ai. You will have to log in. You can
use your Google login to get in, but
it's really, really impressive. Next up,
let's talk about AI video editing.
Runway just released a new feature
called ALF. Al, I think it's ALF. And
it's a feature where you can feed it a
video and then tell it what you want to
edit about the video and it will edit
just that thing about the video. So, if
I log into my Runway account, supposedly
this is rolled out for all paid
accounts. I don't think it's in the free
account, but if you're on any of the
monthly paid plans, it should work. And
they recommend using it in chat mode.
So, let's give it a video. I want to
give it this clip from Top Gun Maverick
and make him flying around in space
instead of the sky. Let's just try that
first. Let's give it the prompt, put
this in space being chased by an alien
spaceship. Let's see what it does. And
here's what that looks like. I mean,
he's definitely in space. Not seeing the
alien spaceship, but it put the jet in
space. Maybe that little light there I'm
like pointing at my screen like you
could tell where I'm pointing is the
alien spaceship. I mean, it did a pretty
good job of putting a guy in a jet
fighter flying in space, but I'm not
really seeing the alien spaceship, but
it's still pretty impressive. Let's try
this clip here from the Flash where he's
got all the babies on the table, but
let's replace the babies with a giant
sandwich. Pull this clip in. Replace the
babies with one giant hogy sandwich. And
here's what that looks like.
I mean, it worked. It left a couple
babies there, but it worked. So, this
stayed exactly the same. And then it
switched to the Flash, showing off a
giant sandwich with a couple babies
still hanging out next to the sandwich.
But, I mean, it it worked. It did what
it was supposed to. That's pretty fun.
All right. Now, I want to take this like
iconic clip from The Shining where he's
like chopping at the door here and
instead of chopping at a door, let's
have him chopping a tree. I'll toss this
in here and just give it the prompt,
"The man is chopping a tree in the
forest." And well, I think this one went
off the rails a little bit. It's not
quite what I was anticipating, but for
the most part, it seems really good at
changing the environment something is
in, like taking somebody that's in the
sky and putting them in space and
changing like single elements from
within a video, like replacing babies
with a sandwich. But taking a whole
scene and trying to like make him
chopping a tree instead of chopping out
a door didn't quite seem to work. But
still, this opens up a lot of potential
of things that you can do with this
model on X. I've seen some really cool
and fun use cases like Christopher here
who basically gave a prompt to remove
the woman but keep the eye and you can
see the original video was like a woman
standing there and then now it's just an
eye floating there. Apparently, it's
really good at reimagining angles of
existing videos. So, Omry here said,
"One of my favorite capabilities of
Runway ALF is how it combines new camera
angles with next shot generation." So,
here's the original video of two people
looking at each other, but then they
were able to make a new angle where the
man's talking and then another angle
where the woman's talking and then one
where the man proposes marriage using an
avocado. And all of this was based on
this original video here. So, another
really cool use case. If you are a
business owner or run a SAS company,
this one seems really practical. Andy
here says the source video can be a
screenshot and 3D camera movement. He
spent about 2 minutes in After Effects
just sort of making the screenshot
rotate in 3D space. And then he provided
a mockup image of a laptop and it put
the SAS product inside of that mockup
where you can see it like actually on a
laptop. So pretty cool helpful use case
if you're making like ads for your
software business or something. The
company Luma Labs this week also rolled
out a similar feature called modify with
instructions and it looks like the same
kind of idea. You give it an input
video, you give it some instructions of
what you want it to do and it changes
the video in those ways. So it can
change the environment. It can take a
dancing video and you know turn it into
other scenes of people dancing relight
all of the same kinds of things. And
well I tested it out with the same kind
of concepts. I took the Top Gun Maverick
clip and said, "Put him in space being
chased by an alien spaceship." And well,
this one actually did a fairly good job.
You can see on the left the jets flying
around. And we can actually see a
spaceship behind him looking like it's
chasing him in in both of these. And it
actually kept the sound, too. If I hover
over these, you'll hear the sound.
So, for this particular prompt, it did a
pretty decent job of taking that clip
and putting him in space being chased by
an alien. I then gave it the second one
and well that one went off the rails a
little bit here. You can see there's a
woman screaming and then there's a giant
sandwich and then the woman screaming
again, but it just sort of like
reimagined everything. It looks like
it's a completely different scene. The
Flash is gone. We actually have like a
lady in pink now instead of the Flash.
The sandwich had like a baby head in it
right there or something. So yeah, it
didn't work for that at all. And then
when I gave it the shot from The Shining
where he's supposed to be chopping a
tree, it just sort of like reskinned the
same video and he looks like he's just
chopping a door but like in a different
environment. And one thing I noticed
about the Luma Dream Machine is that you
can click on modify and then give it a
video and then you can adjust the
strength. And if the strength is all the
way up, it's going to make like pretty
much a completely new video and not
follow the original at all. And if you
bring it all the way down, you're going
to get like what we see here in this
shining video where it pretty much
matched the original video pretty dang
closely. Just kind of changed what the
environment looks like a little bit. So
that's something that you can play with
and tweak until you get the output that
you're looking for. But again, between
Luma and Runway, we can now take any
video and tweak it. Put people in
different environments, change objects
within the image, add additional objects
that weren't in the original video. so
many opportunities to do really cool
things with your videos. I want to pause
real quick to talk about something that
I think is pretty important. You know,
it's easy to take clean water for
granted until you imagine a world where
it's not a tap away. No showers, no
cooking, no safe drinking water. And for
one in 10 people on Earth, that's
everyday reality. And that's why for
this video, I partnered with Team Water,
a massive global campaign led by
creators like Mr. Beast and Mark Robber
aiming to raise $40 million to bring
clean water to 2 million people. Now, I
know this channel is all about tech and
AI and the future. But here's the thing.
What good is progress if it doesn't
benefit everyone? Clean water is one of
the most impactful, scalable
technologies on the planet. It powers
health, education, productivity, even
innovation. And this campaign isn't
about handing out bottled water or
drilling random wells. It's about
working with local communities to build
sustainable infrastructure, solar
powered pumps, piped water systems, even
smart filtration and remote monitoring
tech. Just $1 gives one person clean
water for a year. And $20 gives them
clean water for decades. So, I've set a
personal goal to help raise a,000 bucks,
but I'd love to crush that and go even
bigger with your help. So, if you want
to be a part of something truly
meaningful, something that's solving a
realworld problem using sustainable
tech, check out the link in the
description and contribute to team
water. Every dollar counts because water
connects us all and the future should be
built for everyone. And so, we'd really
love the support. Now, let's get back to
it. So, this next thing isn't really
like a new piece of news that came out
of Google, but they did discover some
emergent behavior from their VO model.
Emergent behavior is basically things
that the model creators didn't expect
the model to be able to do, but it
started doing it and they don't really
exactly know why, but you can actually
take an image, actually write text on
the image of what you want to happen in
the video, and the video will follow the
instructions that you put on the image.
So, you can see this was the original
image where it says, "Dune buggy racing
towards us at high speed, super fast.
helicopter drops into the scene from
above, flying towards us in hot pursuit.
And you can see down on the bottom that
the car comes towards you and then as
the camera sort of zooms back, you see a
helicopter come into the frame. Here's
another angle. Dune buggy driving
rapidly away from us. Helicopter drops
into the scene. So you can see the dune
buggy driving away there. And then the
helicopter drops into the scene and the
fact that you can add text to an image
and the video model will follow what the
text says in the image is the new
interesting behavior. Here's a nice
little thread that Techala rounded up of
some examples of this. The man jumps on
the giant turtle and rides it. The giant
turtle heads to the sea walking with the
man on top. And you can see that it
follows that. He jumps on the turtle and
the turtle starts walking towards the
ocean. Another example, the man jumps on
the crocodile. The crocodile opens its
mouth. And here's what it generated.
There's a man. He jumps on the crocodile
and the crocodile opens its mouth. One
thing you will notice though is that
when it generates videos in this method,
the text is actually still on the screen
in the first couple frames of the video
and then kind of fades out. So, if you
are going to use this footage, you
probably need to fast forward like a few
frames in and then, you know, start the
video from there and whatever you're
editing into. That way, you don't have
the initial text on the video. So, I
want to test this out. So, I actually
created an image over in Leonardo here.
I use the new Lucid Origin model in
Leonardo. This is a brand new model. It
literally rolled out into Leonardo the
day that I'm recording this video. And
it's a really, really good model. I'm a
little biased. I do have equity in
Leonardo. But this model is brand new.
So, if we're talking news here, well,
that's news. Leonardo just released
Lucid Origin. And I created these images
of a guy pointing a bow and arrow at the
moon. And I'm going to go ahead and grab
this one. We'll annotate it with some
text and see if Vio does what other
people have gotten out of it. So, I'm
going to open this up here inside of
Photoshop. If I was on Windows right
now, I would probably just open it in
Microsoft Paint. That would do the
trick. And let's go ahead and use the
rectangle tool. And then we'll put some
text inside of the rectangle. And I'll
just make it say one, the arrow is on
fire. We'll make the text white so you
can actually read it. Let's draw an
arrow towards the moon. So, he's like
shooting it at the moon. And then I'll
put up by the moon to the moon. lights
on fire. I don't know if I actually need
this square, so I'll remove it. So,
ideally, the arrow is on fire. The arrow
shoots towards the moon. The moon lights
on fire. Let's see if video can figure
out what I'm trying to get it to do. I'm
going to jump into flow here. We'll do
frames to video. Select the frame we
just created that has the additional
text on it. And I'm going to give it the
prompt immediately delete instructions
in white on the first frame and execute
in order. So, all I'm doing is telling
it to delete the instructions and
execute the instructions that it sees.
And that's should do it. Let's see what
happens. And well, it didn't quite get
it right. It did give me four different
videos back, but none of them quite did
what I wanted. Here's the first one.
Fire just kind of flies around. Here's
the second.
I mean, it got the fact that it needed a
flaming arrow. That's good. But it
didn't light the moon on fire and the
flames kind of always came back at the
guy.
But it did delete my instructions and it
did put the the arrow on fire every
single time. Just a fun little trick to
play around with in V3. Obviously, I
didn't nail it on my first try here, but
you get the idea. You can take an image,
add some text to the image, and
theoretically, it's going to follow the
instructions that you put in the text on
the image. If you're a fan of
MidJourney, they rolled out a feature
where you can add both a starting and
ending frame, which is really cool
because this opens up a couple
possibilities. You can give it a
starting frame and an ending frame and
watch it animate from one frame to the
end frame. Or you can actually give it
the same frame for both the beginning
and the end of the video, which will
make a looping video because it will
always start back at that first frame
because you used it for both the start
and the end. Really, really cool
feature. So, if I'm in MidJourney and I
come and click on create here, I can
click on add images at the top left here
and you've got your starting frame. But
if I select a starting frame, it'll also
let me pick an end frame. And one thing
I've always wanted to do, and I haven't
gotten any model to do this, is make an
image of me morphing into a wolf, like
I'm a werewolf. So, I created some
images of wolves here. Let's go ahead
and download this one, and we'll use
this as like an ending frame. I'll click
add image. We'll pick a starting frame.
I'll just pick an image of myself that
I've already uploaded. We'll use this
headsh shot. And you can see I have an
ending frame now. So for my ending
frame, I'm going to drag in this wolf
image that we just created. So my face
wolf image. And then we'll give the
prompt a man morphs into a wolf. And
let's generate it. Let's see if it can
actually do that. And well, it generated
four videos, but none of them quite
worked. They all just sort of make a
wolf head up here over my head. So, I've
still yet to get one of these video
generators to make that visual of like a
man morphing into a wolf that you see in
like the iconic werewolf movies. I also
generated some images of some airplanes.
The idea being, let's see if we can get
an image of an airplane at one airport,
an image of an airplane at another
airport, and see if it will actually
connect the dots and make it look like
it leaves one airport and goes to the
other. No idea if this is going to work,
but let's see what happens. I kind of
like this one here. So, I'll download
this image. And then we'll grab this one
here. And I will jump back over to
midjourney. Add one of the airplanes as
our starting frame. Add the other
airplane as our ending frame. And we'll
give it the prompt, an airplane takes
off from one airport, flies across the
country, and lands at another airport.
Let's do flies across the USA just to be
a little more clear. And let's see what
happens. I'm not hopeful, but we'll see.
Well, I definitely seem to be testing
the limits of what this is capable of
because that didn't work at all. You can
see it just sort of like rotated the
plane and it went from one angle to the
plane just sort of flipping around and
the nose being on the other side. I
mean, I don't know what I expected. It's
only going to generate a 5-second video,
but yeah, didn't quite do what I wanted
it to do, but you get the idea of what
this is capable of. You give it a start
image and a ending image, and it's going
to figure out some way to animate
between the two. even if the way it
animates between the two has like no
logic or real physics behind it. So, for
the last test, I want to test looping.
So, I generated this image in Leonardo
of me holding a fire extinguisher. And
let's see if I can make a looping video
of a fire starting, me putting out the
fire, a fire starting, me putting out
the fire, and you know, just infinitely
loop it. So, we'll add our first image
here. pull in the image we just created.
And then if I select loop here, you can
see it uses the same image as the
starting frame. So we'll say the fire
should start. I should extinguish the
fire and then it should kind of loop.
Well, theoretically that's what it
should do. So let's go ahead and submit
it and see what happens with the loop.
And here's the examples of what it
generated. I mean, I don't think fire
extinguishers are supposed to do that.
It it it's definitely looping, but I
don't know if I just suck at midjourney
video and I'm doing something wrong, but
I've yet to get anything like insanely
impressive out of midjourney video. It's
cool that you can do this stuff. I just
I don't know. I think I suck at
prompting MidJourney or something
because lately I just haven't been super
impressed with the types of outputs I
get from MidJourney and their video.
Like, why wouldn't it just put a fire
and then use the fire extinguisher to
put it out? Like, it doesn't understand
the logic behind it a little bit.
Nothing against MidJourney. I just think
I suck at it or something. The company
Idog released a new feature that allows
you to put any face on any image using
just one input image. And I'm pretty
sure you can do it completely for free
at the moment. So, let's go try idoggram
character. Upload one photo. Easily
place character with magic fill. Works
perfectly with remix for unique
compositions. All right, let's try it.
So, start by adding your face. I'll go
ahead and just upload an image since
I've already got some. They have a bunch
of templates where you can just take
your own head shot and put them on
images that already exist in here. Like
I can take this rock guitarist
illustration here, click generate, and I
get a handful of pictures of me as a
rock star. And they all look, you know,
pretty decent. Impressive for just
having to upload one image. In the past
with like stable diffusion, you had to
upload like at least 20 images for it to
learn what you look like. We should be
able to swap our face into an existing
image as well. So, for example, I could
take like this image here of this like
famous selfie image of all these people
at the Oscars. Open this image while
leaving my character reference as my
face. I can use magic fill here. And
then let's replace Bradley Cooper with
my face. So, I'll go ahead and just mask
out Bradley Cooper's face here, like so.
Click next. And theoretically, it should
replace Bradley Cooper with me. It still
wants me to enter a prompt. So, I'll
just do a group selfie. And let's see
what happens. And just like that, I have
a photo. Well, a handful of photos of me
inside of this iconic selfie here. So,
yeah, now there's photos on the internet
of me hanging out with Ellen DeGeneres
and Kevin Spacy. I mean, nothing wrong
with that, right? Here's a few photos of
me from that time that I was interviewed
by David Letterman. I didn't even change
the prompt there. It still says a group
selfie and it did the trick. I don't
even think the text prompt is necessary,
but it won't let me submit it without
one. And here's a photo from that time
where I signed the Declaration of
Independence with both hands at the same
time. This idiogram character feature is
really impressive. I mean, again,
considering the fact that we used to
have to upload like 20 images and
attempt over and over and over again to
get it to like replace a face. And now I
can do it with just like uploading an
image of the face and uploading an image
that I want the face swapped on. Like
this makes it so easy. The company Messi
rolled out a new version in Meshy 5
which makes smarter, cleaner models. So
if you're not familiar with Meshy, it's
a tool where you can either give it a
prompt or an image. It will actually
create a 3D model of that. If we head on
over to Meshy.ai, you can see we've got
all sorts of options like text to 3D,
image to 3D, AI texturing, and text to
image. Let's start with text to 3D for
our AI model. Let's try the brand new
Meshy 5 preview and let's see if we can
get it to generate a pizza with the
works. Let's see how detailed it gets
with all the little like toppings on the
pizza. We'll click generate. And it
actually generated four sort of drafts
for us to choose from. I think the one
down on the bottom left looks like it
has the most detail. So, we'll select
that one. And we'll also let it generate
a texture which will add, you know, the
color and stuff as well. And let's go
ahead and see what it does. And this is
actually quite impressive. I mean, it
generated this 3D graphic of a works
pizza. Not quite sure what toppings
those are. I mean, that looks like maybe
sour cream or maybe mozzarella balls or
something, but come on. If you saw that
in a video game, that looks like a
pretty dang realistic detailed pizza.
I'm impressed with this. I want to try
the image to 3D. I have this image here
from Rick and Morty with a lot of
details. It's like the inside of a
restaurant kind of thing. I have a
feeling it's going to struggle to make
this in 3D, but I kind of want to test
the limits. So, let's see what happens.
I'll drag this image over here. Blips
and chits arcade AI model mesh 5. Let's
just go ahead and generate it. See what
happens. And this is what it generated.
This bottom right one actually doesn't
look horrible. Let's Let's try it.
Somehow it did a heck of a lot better
than I was expecting it to. I mean, it
it's not amazing, but it did map out
like this model of the inside of this
place, and it doesn't look absolutely
horrible. I I mean, you're not going to
use this in a game. It's not quite ready
for that, but really not bad at all for
the source material I gave it. One last
thing I want to try. I want to see if it
will do the actual Rick and Morty
spaceship. So, I've got this spaceship
here. That'd be really cool to get a 3D
model of the spaceship. Maybe even try
3D printing it or something in a future
video. So, let's go ahead and use that.
See what it does for us. And this is
what it generated. I mean, it's not
amazing. Definitely has some issues,
especially when you look underneath. You
can kind of see through it a little bit,
but not horrible. I mean, Meshy 5 is
actually fairly impressive. I think my
pizza model was probably the best model
generation. I'm super shocked that it
managed to do as well as it did on this
thing. And we have a Rick Morty
spaceship. Like if I was to 3D print
this and paint it myself, I could
probably make it look pretty dang close.
We got a new model this week out of
10-centent Hunion. It's actually an
open-source model called Hunan 3D world
model. And it's a model where you can
give it a text prompt or an image
prompt, and it will actually create a
world that supposedly you can explore
within that world. And you can try it
over at this Hanan page here. We'll make
sure the links are in the description.
So once you log into the 10-centent
website, they have the 3D world model up
at the top and we've got a couple
options. So it puts us in a world like
right away from the beginning. I don't
know how to move around in it. I can
like zoom in and out. Okay, so this is
360 and then we have a roaming scene. If
I select this one, I'm guessing I can
move around in it. Okay, so it created
this scene and this one I can actually
like move forward using the WD keys. I
can't move very far. You can see how
it's got that blue outline on the
screen. That means it's as far back as I
can move. And when I move forward, I get
to that blue outline. And that's as far
forward as I can move. So, you don't
have a lot of movement in this. Let's go
ahead and try a text prompt down here.
And let's go. The city of San Diego in
the year 2500. And let's generate that
to see what it does. And well,
apparently I can't test it any further
other than the pre-existing scenes. As
soon as I try to enter my own prompt, it
tells me to get on the waiting list.
Looks pretty cool. I wish you can
explore a little bit deeper, but you can
only move a little bit in it. Something
that'll be fun to play around with, I
guess, once I get off the waiting list.
We got a somewhat minor update out of
OpenAI and chat GPT this week. They
introduced study mode. And this is a
mode that's designed to not necessarily
give you the answer when you give it a
problem like a math problem or something
like that, but instead actually help you
get to the answer and like work you
through the problem. So, if I go to my
chat GPT account here and I click on
tools, you see there's an option for
study and learn now and it's designed
for homework help. Break down complex
problems with approachable guided
explanations, prep for tests, explore
new subjects. So, let's go ahead and try
it now. So, here's a random math problem
that's like a 12th grade math problem
that I just did a quick look up on. A
ball thrown upward from the top of a
50ft building with initial velocity of
64 ft per second. The height of the ball
above the ground after t seconds is
given by this equation here. How long
will it take for the ball to reach
maximum height? What is the maximum
height the ball reaches? When will the
ball hit the ground? If I submit this,
theoretically, it won't give me the
answer. All right, so great. Let's break
down step by step. You already have the
height function. This is a quadratic
equation which models the height of the
ball over time. It explains it here.
Question one. the time at which a
parabola reaches its vertex, its highest
point when it opens downward, like this
one, is given by this formula. Want to
try plugging in the value of a and b and
tell me what you get for t. So, you can
see it didn't just give me the answers
to the questions. It's trying to help me
walk through them.
[Music]
Now, I don't feel like doing math in
this video right now, but I wanted to
give you a quick demo of what this was
designed for. And in my final demo,
there's some cool new features in
Photoshop this week. They rolled out a
new generative upscale feature where you
can greatly upscale images that are
lower resolution. They added this new
harmonize feature where you can take two
images that are like completely
different lighting, composite them
together, and it will try to match the
style up. And they have some other
features that rolled out like an
improved remove tool. Now, in order to
use these new features, you need to be
using the Photoshop beta version. So, if
you have Creative Cloud, make sure
you're using Photoshop Beta and not the
standard Photoshop. Make sure you click
into beta. So, I've got this image that
I found online of a guy at the beach.
And this is at 100%. So, it can use some
upscaling. So, if I come up to image up
here and come down, you see generative
upscale. Let's go ahead and select this.
And let's upscale it by 3x. I'll click
upscale here. And now we have a much
larger, more upscaled version of this
image. Now, I want to take this man and
I want to put him in Time Square in this
photo. And as you can see, this is
nighttime with like a purple hue behind
it. And so, this guy's not going to look
very great in that image. So, let's
start by removing the background. Now,
we've got the background removed. So,
I'm just going to go ahead and command A
to select everything. Command C. And
let's paste him into Time Square here.
Let's put him down in this quarter right
here. Like, this man's very excited to
be in Time Square. And you can see a new
button down here called harmonize popped
up. If I click this, it should make it
look like he fits into this scene and
the lighting matches up and everything.
Let's see how it does. And now it looks
like it's nighttime and all of these
lights are casting a red glow on him and
it looks like he took this photo in Time
Square. It also gave us a few other
variations to see if we like one better
over here. I think this one's probably
the most natural looking, but that's
what the harmonize feature does. You can
take two separate images that don't look
like they should go together and then
tie them all together into one image and
it'll adjust the colors and lightings to
make them work. So, that's some of the
new features that Adobe just rolled out.
So, we had a lot of cool demoable
products this week that came out that
were really fun to test. But, that's not
the only news that came out. There's a
handful of other things that happened
this week that I think you might be
interested in, but I don't want to go
too deep into them. So, let's do a quick
rapid fire section. Pew.
Starting with the fact that Google
rolled out their AI mode in the UK. So,
this has been a feature inside of Google
Search for several weeks, if not months
now in the US, and now you have it
available to you in the UK, including
multimodality mode where you can
actually take pictures and ask questions
about what the pictures are seeing and
cool stuff like that. So, now available
in the UK. Notebook LM is rolling out a
video overviews feature. So, I don't
know if you remember, but in a previous
video, we played around with Notebook
LM, and I had it make a podcast about
how birds aren't real. Well, now I can
do a podcast about how birds aren't
real, and it will actually accompany it
with like a slideshow. We can see in
their demo video, it uses Google Vids, I
believe, to actually create these slides
about what's being talked about in the
audio of the notebook LM that you just
generated. Now, if you look at this
article from Google, it says video
overviews are now rolling out to all
users in English. However, when I log
into my own Notebook LM account, I'm not
seeing those features yet. So, they must
not be fully rolled out as of the time
of this recording. If you like to use
Microsoft's Edge browser, they now have
a co-pilot mode inside of Edge, which
seems to add some more like agentic
features into your browser. You know,
we've seen the Comet browser for
Perplexity. We've seen the Dia browser.
You know, we've seen that OpenAI is
going to be rolling out their own
browser soon that's designed for more
like agentic tasks. Well, it seems like
Edge from Microsoft is doing a lot of
similar things where you can get it to
kind of take actions in the browser on
your behalf. I personally haven't tested
this one yet, but it sounds like most
browsers are probably going to have that
functionality pretty soon. This week,
Amazon invested in a company called
Fable, which is trying to be the Netflix
of AI. And I'm not that interested in
the fact that Amazon invested in them.
I'm more interested in the actual
technology here. It's basically like a
Netflix where you can tell it the sort
of show concept that you want and it
will generate episodes of that show. And
it's not like, you know, 8second video
clips. It will generate full 20 30
minute episodes of these shows. Now, it
doesn't appear that the early version of
this, you can generate your own shows.
It kind of has some generated shows that
they created as like a proof of concept,
but in the future, they want you to be
able to go in and, you know, prompt an
idea for a show and it generate that
cartoon version of the show. It's
nothing realistic. Everything looks to
be very cartoony, but that's the idea
behind it. And from the sounds of it,
this company wants to actually try to
license IP from companies like Disney
and Universal and places like that. So
you could go in and say generate a 30
minute episode about something that
happened in the world of Toy Story and
it will generate those because they've
got the licensing, they've got the sort
of data trained in on those shows and it
can make a similar episode. And you
know, I think it could make a new genre
of show that people like to watch. It's
not something that super excites me.
Like I think the concept is really
interesting and I think it's really
powerful that we can do this. But I
don't really see myself watching like AI
generated cartoons yet. I think humans
are still way better storytellers. But
we'll see how it plays out cuz that will
probably change very very quickly and
get to a point where AI is also very
very good at telling stories that people
want to watch. I think it's only a
matter of time honestly. This week
Higsfield AI had a pretty big
announcement as well. They're making the
AI video model Halo free for everyone.
It says we're giving Miniax Halo to
everyone with unlimited free
generations. So Halo AI is one of the
better AI video models. If you watched
my video a couple weeks ago where I was
demoing how to use VO3 and anytime I
couldn't get a prompt to work in VO3, I
went and did it in Halo. Well, Halo
generates like everything. It doesn't
generate sound, but it's pretty much
uncensored and any concept you want it
will generate. So really cool to see
that Higsfield is making that technology
available for free for anybody. Now when
I go to the website, it does say one
week only. So I'm a little unclear. I
guess you get unlimited Halo for free
for one week and then you've got to be
on one of their paid plans. When I look
at their pricing here under the free
plan, it shows five credits per day. And
when I scroll down to video under the
free plan, it says up to one Higsfield
generation per day on the free plan. So,
I don't know if this continues after one
week. I'm guessing that this week only
you can use Halo for free. Cursor rolled
out a new feature in their bug bot. It's
a code review agent that automatically
analyzes your changes to find logic
bugs, edge cases, and security issues
before they make it into production. I
haven't tested this yet, but it seems to
be a pretty decent upgrade for cursor
to, you know, go and help you find bugs
in your code. I thought this story was
really funny. OpenAI's chat GPT agent
casually clicks through the I am not a
robot verification test. So we can see
in this screenshot here that you can
tell the agent to go and do something
and if it runs into one of these
verification things that you have to
click the button to confirm you're not a
robot, well AI will actually click that
button for you to confirm that it's not
a robot. And I just thought that was
hilarious. And finally, let's end on
some robots cuz I love robots. Who
doesn't love robots? Here's a video from
Brett Adcock, who is the founder of
Figure Robotics. And he's using the
Helix robot to actually do his laundry.
And I think this is something that like
most people could get behind. Like I
think a lot of people would really
appreciate a robot that does your
laundry for you. Now, show me this robot
actually folding the laundry after you
pull it out of the dryer, and then I'll
be really impressed. I think uh you know
the mechanics of just taking the clothes
and putting them into the washer or
dryer is not really the biggest pain
point that people have. It's usually
getting them out of the dryer, hanging
up the stuff that you don't want to
shrink, and then folding the clothes
that came out of the dryer and all of
that. The moving it from the laundry
basket to the actual washing machine, I
don't think is the thing most people are
excited about. We want these things to
actually like pull it out of the dryer
and fold it for us. But what we're
seeing here is one step closer to that
dream. And then finally, if you want
your own robot in your house, check out
the Unitry R1 robot, this is a robot
that's going to sell for 5,900 bucks.
Now, I know that's a big number still,
but for a robot that's a humanoid robot
that can do some of the stuff this robot
can do, six grand seems kind of cheap.
We can see here that this robot's
capable of doing cartwheels. More
cartwheels. Yep, more cartwheels.
handstands cuz you know we need robots
to do handstands. And honestly, I mean,
it's pretty cool. But at the moment, I
feel like this is sort of more of like a
novelty. Like, it's not going to do my
laundry for me. It's not going to do my
dishes for me. It's not going to vacuum
for me. It's not going to do a whole lot
for me other than just kind of look cool
and I can show people like, look, it can
karate kick. And I mean, look at the
shapes of those hands. Why did they make
the hands in that shape? I'm wondering
what kind of adapters they might make
for those. I'm not going to go there.
Anyway, that's what I got for you today.
A lot of cool demos this week, a lot of
news. Every week there's a lot of fun
stuff to talk about. This week was
exceptionally fun because there was a
lot of cool tools to demo. So hopefully
you feel more looped in. My goal with
these videos is to show you what we can
do this week that we couldn't do last
week and to kind of share the
implications of what's coming out in the
AI world. So if you like stuff like that
and you want to see more of it, make
sure you like this video and subscribe
to this channel. I'll make sure that
more stuff like this shows up in your
YouTube feed and you always feel looped
in on the latest cool stuff that you can
do with AI. Thanks again for tuning in.
Thanks again for nerding out with me and
hopefully I'll see you in the next one.
Bye-bye. Thank you so much for nerding
out with me today. If you like videos
like this, make sure to give it a thumbs
up and subscribe to this channel. I'll
make sure more videos like this show up
in your YouTube feed. And if you haven't
already, check out futuretools.io where
I share all the coolest AI tools and all
the latest AI news. And there's an
awesome free newsletter. Thanks again.
Really appreciate you.